{
    "id": "ce6bbf5f0b7147e19540627c9f767640",
    "title": "Gerunds And Participles",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He is fond …………………….. cricket.",
            "description": "Certain adjectives are followed by ‘preposition + ing form’.",
            "answers": [
                "to play",
                "of playing",
                "of to play"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d414566c34f14f1b991ceebb39c27f9f"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… along the road, he found a dead cobra.",
            "description": "When we split the clauses we get: \r\nHe was walking along the road\r\nHe found a dead cobra.\r\nWe can connect them with the present participle ‘walking’.",
            "answers": [
                "Walking",
                "To walk",
                "Having walked"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "05d3bfd7dbc644c4984adfa99cef66e6"
        },
        {
            "question": "We were prevented …………………………. the patient.",
            "description": "The verb prevent is followed by 'preposition + ing form’.",
            "answers": [
                "to see",
                "from seeing",
                "to seeing"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "731875b5c12947a9b08d4f70940fec4c"
        },
        {
            "question": "I hope you will excuse …………………………… leaving early.",
            "description": "The word leaving is a gerund that serves the same purpose as a noun. We cannot use an object pronoun to modify a noun instead we use a possessive adjective (my).",
            "answers": [
                "me",
                "my",
                "I"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d6edcea3ce8a4a32b25f1fc36ecc871f"
        },
        {
            "question": "We rejoiced at ………………………….. being promoted.",
            "description": "The word being is a gerund that serves the same purpose as a noun. We cannot use an object pronoun to modify a noun instead we use a possessive adjective (his).",
            "answers": [
                "him",
                "he",
                "his"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3ebc7a1ad0f7482db9f7ccdf82d5161d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I insist on ………………………… being present at the meeting.",
            "description": "The word being is a gerund that serves the same purpose as a noun. We cannot use an object pronoun to modify a noun instead we use a possessive adjective (your).",
            "answers": [
                "you",
                "your",
                "yours"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4861f69188874e3d80ad7f56193bd911"
        },
        {
            "question": "We left without ……………………….. knowing.",
            "description": "The word knowing is a gerund that serves the same purpose as a noun. We use a possessive expression to modify a noun. ",
            "answers": [
                "anyone",
                "anyone's",
                "anyones"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "51b2e637d9b144589e9a5bfcda939ada"
        },
        {
            "question": "All depends on ………………………… passing the exam.",
            "description": "The word passing is a gerund that serves the same purpose as a noun. We use a possessive expression to modify a noun. ",
            "answers": [
                "John",
                "John's"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "45e0b9dd1149450ea864409328dbcfba"
        },
        {
            "question": "It ……………………… a very hot day, I remained in my tent.",
            "description": "It was a very hot day. I remained in my tent. We can combine them with the participle being.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "being",
                "been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e8572f9b27d344f6bc7244d00a1eadfe"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………… across the heath, a gipsy found the child.",
            "description": "A gypsy was wandering across the heath. He found the child. \r\nWe can combine them with the present participle wandering.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "Wandered",
                "Wandering",
                "Having wandered"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8f7c2dc96304407e91703c32103cb53b"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………….. his lesson, he went out to play.",
            "description": "He had learned his lesson. He went out to play. We can combine them with the perfect participle ‘having learned’.",
            "answers": [
                "Learning",
                "Learned",
                "Having learned"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "720f0e8354d745aca01fd6894039fc4b"
        },
        {
            "question": "We met an old man …………………………….. to Jerusalem.",
            "description": "We met an old man. He was walking to Jerusalem.\r\nWe can combine the two clauses with the present participle ‘walking’.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "walking",
                "walked"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "112d2bbc077a41389c1f2492f1fd93f3"
        }
    ]
}